(
"ai_sub_version": "3.0.3",
"generated_at": "2026-07-04T02:12:00.250648",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 16,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
雲を割って洩れ注ぐ light ray
Light rays breaking through the clouds
濡れた駅は眩しさに包まれる
The wet station is wrapped in brilliance
旅立ちのホーム振り向く笑顔
A smiling face turning back on the platform of departure
前途洋々！明るく君はそう言って
Future prospects! You said so brightly
見送る僕にピースを振った step into the dream
You waved a peace sign at me seeing you off, step into the dream
僕もここで頑張るよ promise
I will do my best here too, promise
指を切った感触が切ないよ
The feeling of our pinky promise is so sad
動き出す瞳視線で追った
I followed your moving eyes with my gaze
何て言ったの？電車が声を連れ去って
What did you say? The train carried your voice away
一瞬君の光った頬が step into the dream
For a moment, your shining cheek, step into the dream
旅立ちの二人微かな恋に
For the two of us departing, in our faint love
前途洋々！心で強く言い聞かせ
Future prospects! Telling myself strongly in my heart
踏み出す君に負けずに僕も
Not to lose to you taking your step, I will also
step into the dream step into the dream
3周年ありがとう！これからもずっと君と一緒に！
[Text: Thank you for the 3rd anniversary! I want to be with you forever!]
ホロライブに入る！！
[Text: I will join Hololive!!]
不採用
[Text: Rejected]
碧青
作詞・作曲：Ayase
[Song: Gunjou / Lyrics & Composition: Ayase]
あぁ、いつものように
Ah, just like usual,
過ぎる日々にあくびが出る
I yawn at the passing days.
さんざめく夜、越え、今日も
Crossing a noisy night, today again,
渋谷の街に朝が降る
morning falls upon the city of Shibuya.
どこか虚しいような
Feeling somewhat empty,
そんな気持ち
that kind of feeling...
つまらないな
How boring.
でもそれでいい
But that is fine,
そんなもんさ
that's just how it is.
これでいい
This is fine.
知らず知らず隠してた
Inadvertently hiding away
本当の声を響かせてよ、ほら
my true voice, let it resonate, look!
見ないフリしていても
Even if you pretend not to see,
確かにそこにある
it is certainly right there.
感じたままに描く
Drawing just as I feel,
自分で選んだその色で
with the colors I chose myself.
眠い空気纏う朝に
In the morning wearing a drowsy atmosphere,
訪れた青い世界
a blue world visited me.
好きなものを好きだと言う
Saying that I like what I love...
怖くて仕方ないけど
I can't help but be terrified,
本当の自分、出会えた気がしたんだ
but I felt like I could finally meet my true self.
あぁ、手を伸ばせば伸ばすほどに
Ah, the more I reach my hands out,
遠くへゆく
the further away it goes.
思うようにいかない今日も
Even today, when things don't go as planned,
また慌ただしくもがいてる
I am struggling, flustered once again.
悔しい気持ちも
Even this frustrating feeling,
ただ情けなくて涙が出る
it's just so pathetic that it brings tears to my eyes.
踏み込むほど
The further I step in,
苦しくなる
the harder it gets,
痛くもなる
and the more painful it becomes.
感じたままに進む
Moving forward just as I feel,
自分で選んだこの道を
on this path I chose myself.
重いまぶた擦る夜に
On the night of rubbing my heavy eyelids,
しがみついた青い誓い
I clung onto my blue vow.
好きなことを続けること
To keep doing what I love...
それは楽しいだけじゃない
it is not just fun all the time.
本当にできる？
Can I really do this?
不安になるけど
I get so anxious, but...
あぁ、何枚でも
Ah, no matter how many times,
ほら、何枚でも
look, no matter how many times...
あー あー
Ah, ah...
何回でも ほら何回でも
No matter how many times, see, no matter how many times,
積み上げてきたことが武器になる
everything I've built up will become my weapon.
周りを見たって 誰と比べたって
Even if I look around, even if I compare myself to others,
僕にしかできないことはなんだ
what is it that only I can do?
今でも自信なんか無い それでも
Even now, I still have no confidence. Even so...
感じたことのない気持ち
A feeling I've never felt before,
知らずにいた想い
emotions I never knew existed,
あの日踏み出して
stepping forward on that day...
初めて感じたこの痛みも全部
Even all of this pain that I felt for the first time,
好きなものと向き合うことで
by facing what I love,
触れたまだ小さな光
I touched a still-tiny light.
大丈夫、行こう
It's okay, let's go.
生誕ライブスタート、イェーイ！
My birthday live is starting, yay!
ちょっとめちゃくちゃに緊張しているんですけれども
I'm super, super nervous, but...
どうだった？群青のアイリスアウト、コメント欄どうだった？かっこよかった？
How was it? Gunjou no Iris Out? How was the comment section? Was it cool?
かっこよかったって、きっと、まあこの後流れるんだろうな。かっこよかっただろ！
I'm sure they said it was cool, well, those comments will probably flow by later. It was cool, right?!
いっぱい褒めてください。
Please shower me with praises.
今回はですね、タイトルにもある通り、もうステップがもうはちゃめちゃに、ステップがステップがもうはちゃめちゃに多かったりですね
This time, as the title suggests, there are so many steps, like, the steps, the steps are just insanely numerous...
あとは、やったことのないジャンルのダンスにも挑戦しちゃったりしていますので
And I'm also challenging myself with dance genres I've never done before,
お楽しみに！
So please look forward to it!
ハッシュタグは、こちらにあるハッシュタグ、#水宮すう生誕祭2026 です！
The hashtag is this one here: #MizumiyaSuBirthday2026!
スクショとか、感想とかたくさんポストしてくれると嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you post lots of screenshots and impressions!
目指せトレンド！みんな、いっぱいポストしてねー！
Aim for trending! Everyone, post a lot!
この後はですね、ゲストパートにも行きたいと思っているのですが…
After this, I'd like to move on to the guest part, but...
なんと、お祝いの映像が届いてるみたいなので、見てみましょう！
Surprisingly, it seems we received a congratulatory video message, so let's watch it!
こっちかな？
Is it over here?
よし。
Alright.
なんだなんだ？
What is it, what is it?
きみの笑顔をご案内！ランハナの観光大使、にじさんじ所属、彩虹の末っ子、シガリコだよ！
Guiding your smile! Lan-Hana's tourism ambassador, Nijisanji's youngest of the Ayakaki, I am Shigariko!
水宮！お誕生日おめでとう！
（りこ！ありがとう！）
Mizumiya! Happy birthday!
(Riko! Thank you!)
きっと今、水宮は最高のライブをしていることでしょう！
Right now, Mizumiya must be putting on the best live performance!
本当に、本当におめでとう！
（すうの、ありがとう！）
Congratulations, truly!
(Thank you!)
本当はね、現地で直接お祝いがしたかったんですけど、どうしてもスケジュールが合わないということで、お祝いのメッセージ動画をね、今回送らせていただいております！
I really wanted to celebrate with you directly on-site, but since our schedules didn't match no matter what, I'm sending this congratulatory message video!
水宮とはね、ロロメロとしてもうたくさんコラボして、プライベートとかでもテーマパーク行ったりとか
（行った！）
I've done so many collabs with Mizumiya as Lolomelo, and in private, we went to theme parks...
(We did!)
映画も行ったりとか、月一でお泊まりするくらいの
（行った！）
...and to the movies, and we even sleep over about once a month.
(We did!)
超仲良くね、させてもらってて、本当にいつもありがとう！
（ありがとう！）
We're super close, so thank you so much for everything!
(Thank you!)
事務所がね、違うのにもこんな仲良くなれるなんて、もうめっちゃ嬉しいですし
Even though our agencies are different, I'm so happy we could become this close.
いつも水宮に元気もらって、支えてもらってます。
I'm always getting energy and support from you, Mizumiya.
これからも、ずーっと友達！いっぱい遊んで、いっぱい楽しいことしていこうね！大好きだよ！
（友達！いっぱい遊ぼう！）
Let's be friends forever! Let's hang out a lot and do lots of fun things! I love you!
(Friends! Let's play a lot!)
それでは、シガリコでした！この後もライブ楽しんでね！頑張れ！
（ありがとう！）
Well, that was Shigariko! Enjoy the rest of your live! Good luck!
(Thank you!)
うわーー！
Wow!
ということで、シガリコからメッセージが届きました、ありがとう、シガリコ！こっちにいるかな？ありがとう、シガリコ！
So, I got a message from Shigariko, thank you Shigariko! Is she over here? Thank you, Shigariko!
いや、そう、今回はね、ちょっとスケジュールが合わなくて、ちょっとリコの3Dにはね、ちょっと呼んでもらって、一緒に踊ったんですけど
Yes, our schedules didn't match this time. I was invited to Riko's 3D live stream and we danced together,
ちょっとすうのライブでは今回は、踊れなかったけど、いつか一緒にまた踊ろうな！ありがとうね、リコ！水宮頑張るよ！
but we couldn't dance together in my live stream this time. Let's dance together again someday! Thank you, Riko! Mizumiya will do her best!
応援してもらったし、ちょっと次の曲にいこうかな？ちょっと次はゲストパートだから、誰が来るのかな？
Since I got her support, shall we go to the next song? Next is the guest part, so I wonder who's coming?
この後も、まだまだ続きます！そしてなんか告知もあるかもしれないので、最後まで楽しんでね！
There's still more to come! And we might have some announcements, so please enjoy until the end!
昔々のそのまた昔 とある貴族の仲良しな兄弟
Once upon a time, long, long ago, in a certain noble house, there lived a pair of inseparable siblings
（以下略称）
(Et cetera, et cetera)
「ちゃんとやれ！」
"Do it properly!"
じいやが呼ぶ 席につけ よーいどん！
The butler calls, "Take your seats, ready, go!"
ナイフとフォークで応戦いたしますの
We fight with knives and forks
だって僕らはブルジョアの
Because we are of the bourgeoisie
立派な立派な貴族様なんですですの
A noble, a noble, a noble lord, that's what we are
ひれふせ愚民 君との違いを
Bow down, you commoners, can't you see the difference between you and us?
ヴァイヴァイスロイ 見せてやるぜ
Vice-viceroy, we'll show you!
おい まてまて また勝手にそんな
Hey, wait, wait, what are you doing on your own again?
見ぬけるようなハッタリかまして
Setting up some transparent bluffing
はーい はーい はい はい
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
お兄様の仰せのままに（笑）
As you command, my lord (lol)
あーむかつくぜ！ まーじむかつくぜ！
Ah, it's so annoying! It's really so annoying!
兄に対して 生意気な態度
That insolent attitude toward your elder sibling
閧の声 ゴングを鳴らせ
Sound the battle cry, ring the gong
ケンカ勃発で宣戦布告
The fight breaks out, a declaration of war
悪戯して 悪ノリして
Playing pranks, egging each other on
ほらほら 煽ってくStyleで
Look, look, it's our style to keep riling things up
大安売り 買っちゃったら
"Big sale," if you buy it,
毎度ありがとうで君の負け！
Thanks as always, you lose!
（っしゃぁ！）
(Yeah!)
拙い引き出しと 煽りあいの駆け引きでキメる
With my clumsy repertoire and our back-and-forth provocation, I'll clinch it
兄の威厳見せるため飴と鞭 火花散る散る両者の目と目
To show my elder brother's dignity, a mixture of candy and whips, sparks flying, eyes meeting eyes
くらえ！おれさまがルールブック
Take this! I am the rule book
へたれじゃない ひよってない ちょっと勇気が足りないだけ
I'm not a coward, I'm not chickening out, I'm just a little short on courage
さぁさぁみなさん お手を拝借 当たり前だろ 余裕しゃくしゃく
Come on, come on, everyone, lend us a hand, it's obvious, I'm cool, calm, and collected
生まれながらにしてチート やべぇ煌めく人生がスタート
Born a cheat, oh, a sparkling life begins!
当然です見てみな由緒はガチ勢
Of course! Look at my pedigree, I'm a pro!
ハイ論破 ハイ論破 ハイ論破
High, rebuttal, high, rebuttal, high, rebuttal
はーい！はーい！はーい！はーい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
はなまるよくできました☆
You get a gold star! Well done! ☆
あーむかつくぜ まーむかつくぜ
Ah, I'm so annoyed! Seriously, I'm so annoyed!
僕に向かって減らず口なんざ
Spouting such cheekiness to me!
とっておきを君に見舞え
I'll unleash my best trick on you!
報復制裁 挑発しちゃって保存
Retaliation and punishment, teasing you!
意地悪して一枚上手
Playing mean, I'm one step ahead!
チャンスはもらってくぜ
I'm taking this opportunity!
痛恨ミス あっ ちゃっ ちゃー
A critical mistake! Oh, my goodness!
おあいにく様だね 君の負け保存
Too bad for you, you lose!
Yes!
だけど君 君だけが
But you, only you...
僕に似合いのライバル
...are a rival worthy of me.
落ちるのも へこんでんのも保存
Falling down or feeling depressed,
調子狂わされるから
you throw me completely off my rhythm,
今宵もテメエと やい！やい！やい！やい！
so tonight again, with you, let's fight! Fight! Fight! Fight!
やい！
Fight!
大体お前がいつも暴走するから僕が尻拭いせざるを得なくなるんだろ！何言ってんの！
Since you always run wild, I have to clean up after you! What are you talking about?!
年上のくせに頼りにならない！慎重なフリしたってヘタレてたぞほんともう！
Even though you're older, you're so unreliable! You act cautious but you were just chickening out!
ハイ決定！
It's decided!
あーむかつくぜ まーむかつくぜ
Ah, I'm so annoyed! Seriously, I'm so annoyed!
憎まれ口もお口をチャック
Zip your mouth with those abusive remarks!
鬨の声 ゴングを鳴らせ
A battle cry! Sound the gong!
次世代エンペラーはこの俺だ
The next generation emperor is me!
悪戯して 悪乗りして
Playing pranks, getting carried away!
ほらほら煽ってくスタイルで
Look, look, this is our style of teasing!
1から100 いただきます
From 1 to 100, thank you for the feast!
毎度ありがとうで君の負け
Thanks as always, and you lose!
まさかの
Could it be...
引き分け！？
...a draw?!
えーーーっ！
Whaaat?!
この頃君がまとう しつけ直しの季節の匂い
Lately you wear the scent of a season of re-discipline.
したたかな佇まいのわりに脆い そこに触れるの
Despite your tough posture, you are fragile when I touch you there.
怒らないでダーリン だってホントのことだもん
Don't be mad, darling, because it's the truth after all.
体ばかり大きくなって中身はガキだよね
Your body has grown big, but you're still a kid inside.
あばれないでドッグ 私が主の手だから
Don't wild out, dog, because I am the hand of your master.
リードなんて気まぐれ パッと外しちゃうかも
The leash is whimsical; I might just take it off in a flash.
だらしない 意気地ない ホント君は救えない
Sloppy, spineless, you're truly beyond saving.
堕落にふけっちゃってご愁傷様
Drowning in depravity, my condolences.
夢がない 覇気もない くせに愛は欲しいの？
No dreams, no ambition, yet you still want love?
なら3回回ってお手からワン
Then spin three times, give me your paw, and bark.
ルルルルッ テュルルル
Lu lu lu... tyu ru ru...
欲深だったの？ 歪み 妬み 人の宝物
Were you greedy? Distorted, jealous of other people's treasures.
この世は罠だらけね ずっとここにいて
This world is full of traps, stay here forever.
手なずけてた奥義 生まれ持った才知のすべて
The secrets I tamed, all of your inborn wit.
全部狂わせて今日も正常？ 私と舞いな
Drive everything crazy, today is normal too? Dance with me.
あがいたって餌捌き次第ね 私は知らない
Even if you struggle, it's up to my feeding skill. I don't care.
私、主を知らなかった頃の日々に戻りたい
I want to return to the days before I knew my master.
Our love is trapped
We'll lose our way if we lose our track
もう、主を知らなかった頃の君は戻らない
The you from before you knew your master will never return.
どうせ誰も聴いてないさ
Nobody's listening anyway.
音楽なんて全部ファッション 音亡喰らって選手退場ワンナイ
Music is just fashion, take the blow and exit, one night.
どうせ何も伝えてなんかないさ
You're not conveying anything anyway.
なんとかトック撮って売名 あんな気取っておいて最低グンナイ
Doing whatever Tok to gain fame, acting all cool, you're the worst, good night.
どうしたってどうみたって尊師達でもう大渋滞
No matter how you look at it, it's crowded with gurus.
それでもあっち、こっち、そっち、ぼっち、卍、Zエイジ
Still, here, there, everywhere, alone, Z-generation.
猿も欲しがるパンチライン欲しいの 意味とかどっちだっていいよ元々
Even monkeys want a punchline, who cares about the meaning.
歌詞とかどうでもいいのでノれるの下さい
Lyrics don't matter, just give me something to vibe to.
さあ皆で笑いましょう 芸術より数の大小？
Come on, let's all laugh, size of numbers over art?
ヴァイラスに酷い代償 じゃあどうすんの？
A terrible price for the virus, so what are you gonna do?
それでいいんだっけ？
Is that really okay?
頭は空回り タヒんでいく
My head spins in circles, dying out.
(I found myself instead) ふざけるな
(I found myself instead) Don't mess around!
バイバイ バズメロディ
Bye-bye, buzz melody.
疑えよ大概 嘘ばかり
Doubt it, most of it is just lies.
化けんな幻想でも理想でも良い
Don't turn into a phantom, fantasy or ideal is fine.
君の歌いたかった物はどうしたんだい？
What happened to the thing you wanted to sing?
ぶざまでもオーライ 嘘じゃない
Even if it's pathetic, it's alright, it's not a lie.
お金や擬奏で満たす前に
Before filling yourself with money or fake play.
負けんな覚醒せよ鼓動達よ
Don't lose, awaken, you beating hearts.
君の伝えたかった物はどうしたんだい？
What happened to the thing you wanted to convey?
意味わかんねぇ！
I don't get it!
お書きになったそんな音楽は現在使われておりません。ポップソング、ヒットソング聴いて、もう一度お書き直しください。
The music you have written is not currently in use. Please listen to pop songs, hit songs, and rewrite it.
あーもうハイカラ作家ばっか洒落くさいわ はぁ…
Ah, all these trendy writers are so annoying, sigh...
どいつもこいつもそいつもあいつも意味わかんねぇ！
Every single one of them makes no sense!
どうしたってどうみたって尊師達でもう大渋滞
No matter how you look at it, it's crowded with gurus.
それでもあっち、こっち、そっち、ぼっち、卍、Zエイジ
Still, here, there, everywhere, alone, Z-generation.
猿も欲しがるパンチライン欲しいの 意味とかどっちだっていいよ
Even monkeys want a punchline, who cares about the meaning.
歌詞とかどうでもいいので伸びるの下さい
Lyrics don't matter, just give me something that will grow.
さあ皆で祓いましょう 芸術より数なんでしょう？
Come on, let's exorcise it all, it's about numbers over art, right?
ヴァイラスに酷い代償 じゃあどうすんの？
A terrible price for the virus, so what are you gonna do?
それでいいんだっけ？
Is that really okay?
頭は空回り タヒんでいく
My head spins in circles, dying out.
(I found myself instead) ふざけるな
(I found myself instead) Don't mess around!
バイバイ バズメロディ
Bye-bye, buzz melody.
疑えよ大概 嘘ばかり
Doubt it, most of it is just lies.
化けんな幻想でも理想でも良い
Don't turn into a phantom, fantasy or ideal is fine.
君の歌いたかった物はどうしたんだい？
What happened to the thing you wanted to sing?
このままじゃ到底終われ
I can't possibly end it like this.
欲しいのはきっとお金じゃない
What I want is surely not money.
負けんな覚醒せよ鼓動達よ
Don't lose, awaken, you beating hearts.
君の歌いたかった物がきっとあるんだ
There's surely something you wanted to sing.
ふざけるな… ふざけるな！
Don't mess around... Don't mess around!
バイバイ バズメロディ
Bye-bye, buzz melody.
疑えよ大体 嘘ばかり
Doubt it, mostly it's just lies.
化けんな幻想でも理想でも良い
Don't turn into a phantom, fantasy or ideal is fine.
君の歌いたかった物はどうしたんだい？
What happened to the thing you wanted to sing?
ぶざまでもオーライ 嘘じゃない
Even if it's pathetic, it's alright, it's not a lie.
お金や擬奏で満たす前に
Before filling yourself with money or fake play.
負けんな覚醒せよ鼓動達よ
Don't lose, awaken, you beating hearts.
君の伝えたかった物はどうしたんだい？
What happened to the thing you wanted to convey?
意味わかんねぇ！
I don't get it!
意味わかんねぇよ！意味わかんねぇ！
I don't get it! I don't get it at all!
意味わかんねぇ
I don't get it.
せーの
Ready, set...
すーちゃんお誕生日おめでとう！ / ありがとう！
Happy Birthday, Suu-chan! / Thank you!
おめでとう！やったー！
Congratulations! Yay!
何歳になったわけ？
How old did you turn?
20歳バージョン2！
20 years old, version 2!
ありがとう！ありがとう！ちょっとみんなせっかく来て...
Thank you! Thank you! Guys, since you came all this way...
ありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
あんた転ぶでしょ
You're going to fall.
でもさ、今日の主役ですから、みずみあは！
But you know, Mizumia is today's main star!
みんなに一言言ってね、去ってもらおうかなって
Let's have everyone say a word before they leave.
一人ずつ、ほら、すーに愛をね、一言言ってね
One by one, show Suu some love with a brief message.
誰から？ほら / いや / うん
Who's first? Come on. / No. / Yeah.
ママだよ。
I'm your mama.
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
もうほらちゃんと聞いて。
Come on, listen properly.
変な人いて怖かったでしょ。
It was scary with weird people around, right?
ママだよ。違うよ、違うよ！
I'm your mama. No, you're not! No, you're not!
ほら、残りの二人、残りの二人！
Look, the remaining two! The remaining two!
俺がママだ！ちょっと待って、ちょっと待って！
I am the mama! Wait a minute, wait a minute!
別に芸能事務所のそれじゃないのよ、芸人じゃないのよ。
This isn't an entertainment agency, we are not comedians!
これからもお姉ちゃんに頼ってね！
Keep relying on your big sister from now on!
お姉ちゃんと思ってるの？本当に。おかしいよ！
Do you really think of her as a big sister? That's weird!
ほら、ちゃんと、ほら、愛をね、最後に。
Come on, show some love at the end.
あの、スビビの中やんか
You know, we're Subibi, aren't we?
そうね
That's right.
だから「せーの」って言ったら何言うかわかるよな？
So if we say "Ready, set...", you know what to say, right?
わかった
Got it.
せーの...
Ready, set...
スビビ！最強！
Subibi! Strongest!
待って、待って！
Wait, wait!
なんで？
Why?
あ、思ってた、思ってた
Ah, I thought so, I thought so.
せーの...
Ready, set...
スビビ最強！
Subibi is the strongest!
ありがとう
Thank you!
タッチ、タッチして
Give me a high-five!
大丈夫？届けられる？
Are you okay? Can you reach?
ありがとうね、みんな
Thank you, everyone.
ありがとう、頑張ってね
Thank you! Do your best!
ママ、良かったよ
Mom, you did great.
タッチ、タッチ！ありがとう！
High-five, high-five! Thank you!
バイバイ！がんばれー！
Bye-bye! Good luck!
なんか、うるさかったな
Man, they were noisy.
頑張るか。よし
Alright, let's do this.
くだらない愛の結果で 僕らは生まれ落ちて
By the result of a trivial love, we were born into this world,
呼吸さえしあぐねているけれど
struggling even just to breathe.
綺麗な言葉並べて 醜さに蓋をして
Lining up pretty words, covering up the ugliness,
自分を愛せないままだな、ずっと
I still can't love myself, even now, always...
くだらない嘘を言う度 青い色こぼれ落ちた
Every time I told a trivial lie, a blue color spilled out.
ガラスの瞳が綺麗で
Your glass eyes were so beautiful.
君のその瞼のように 優しい人になってさ
I want to become a kind person, just like your eyelids,
そんな僕を愛したいんだよ
and love myself like that.
私の呼吸に終わりがあること
My breath will eventually come to an end,
君の声を覚えている
but I will still remember your voice.
生まれては消えていくこと それだけを繰り返している
Being born and then fading away, we repeat only that.
僕らがもしまた会えたらだなんて思ってた
I kept thinking, "What if we could meet again?"
生まれては消えていく日々の 青白い波に名前をつけることに
To give a name to the pale blue waves of these days that are born and fade,
意味はなかったのかな、なんてさ
I wondered if there was no meaning to it at all...
たわいない忙しさみたい 積み木で遊んでいる
Like a silly busyness, playing with building blocks,
崩れるその日を待っている
waiting for the day they collapse.
澄みきった夜 of 静寂は 君の頬の赤色で
The clear silence of the night, colored by the red of your cheeks,
もうすぐ桜が咲くんだろう
soon the cherry blossoms will bloom.
僕らの呼吸に意味がなくても
Even if there is no meaning to our breathing,
二人はまた恋をする
the two of us will fall in love again.
生まれては消えていくこと それだけを繰り返している
Being born and then fading away, we repeat only that.
そして君も夜の海に帰っていくんだろう
And you, too, will return to the night sea.
生まれては消えていく日々の 青白い波に名前をつけることに
To give a name to the pale blue waves of these days that are born and fade,
囚われている
we are trapped.
覚えているかな
Do you remember...
いつかの春の朝に
...on some spring morning...
桜の木の下で
...under the cherry blossom tree,
約束したこと
the promise we made?
思い出も君の名前も いつの日か失ってしまって
My memories and even your name, someday they will be lost,
僕もいつかこの海と一つになるんだろう
and I, too, will someday become one with this sea.
君のいない冬の空気が 僕の頬を刺すその痛みさえ
Even the pain of the winter air without you piercing my cheek,
愛していたい
I want to love it.
生まれては消えていくこと それだけを繰り返している
Being born and then fading away, we repeat only that.
僕らがもしまた会えたらだなんて思ってた
I kept thinking, "What if we could meet again?"
生まれては消えていく日々の 青白い波に名前をつけることに
To give a name to the pale blue waves of these days that are born and fade,
意味はなかったのかな、なんてさ
I wondered if there was no meaning to it at all...
こうして冬が終わって
And so, winter comes to an end,
青い春が来る
and blue spring arrives.
Unhappy? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? O troubled child of humanity.
Unlucky? 人ならざるものも
Unlucky? And even those who are not human,
Be happy! まずは目指せよ
Be happy! First, aim for it!
生きているんだし
After all, you're alive.
目を逸らした過去も
Both the past you averted your eyes from,
退屈な未来も
and the boring future,
カウンセリング やれやれ
it's time for counseling, oh dear.
古今東西 ピースピース
Through all times and places, peace, peace!
Unhappy?
Unlucky?
Be happy!
アンデッド
Undead!
ねえねえねえ なんだかどうして
Hey, hey, hey, why is it that somehow
戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
I feel like I'm fighting?
触れられない 過去の自分
With my untouchable past self,
自分 自分 自分と
myself, myself, myself.
もうとっくに死んでる
Fighting against a transparent ghost
透明な亡霊と対決
that's already long dead.
幼気で痛い 記憶の奥
Deep in my innocent, painful memories,
残念 もう居ないのに あれ？
how disappointing, they're no longer there... Wait?
そっちが良い？アイロニーね
Do you prefer that? How ironic.
透かされているのは現在の自分？
Is it my current self that's being seen through?
ナンセンス 消えないレッテル
Nonsense, an indelible label,
要はコンプレックス
essentially, a complex.
取り憑かれているみたい
It feels like I'm possessed,
巻き付いたまま
wrapped around me...
まだ離れない 在りし日の自分
...still not letting go, my past self from those bygone days.
死んじゃいない
You're not dead,
お前とお前の連鎖
the chain of you and your past.
生きているということは変わり続けることだ
To live is to keep changing.
不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ
Don't content yourself by wallowing in unhappiness.
幸せになろうとしないなんて嘘だ
It's a lie to say you're not trying to be happy.
この世、この世は奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
This world is a bizarre, bizarre fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか 蛇が出るか
Will a demon appear next, or a snake?
出会って違ってやっと始まる物語
Meeting, being different, the story finally begins.
さあ人か化け物か 覚悟は良い？ピースピース
Now, are you human or monster? Are you ready? Peace, peace!
Past & Future, can't change the past
Past & Future, run for the future
なんだかどうして 未来になんぞ何の
Somehow, why does it feel like there's nothing
期待も出ないような気がして
to expect from the future?
もう随分生きてる
I've been alive for quite a while now.
既視感とテンプレで食傷
Fed up with déjà vu and clichés,
素敵な出来事の気配もない
there's no sign of anything wonderful happening.
残念 積んだ経験の
Disappointing, the fossilization of accumulated experience,
形骸化された形ばかりの進化
a mere formal evolution that's lost its substance.
退屈な進化
A boring evolution.
要は刺激が欲しい
In short, I want some excitement.
飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった
I'm tired of it, I've got used to it.
整っていくガイダンス
Guidance falling into place,
増えるコンプライアンス
increasing compliance,
蓋されていくみたい
it feels like being shut in.
退屈して
Bored,
あれもこれもどれも同じ味がする
everything tastes the same.
死んじゃいない
You're not dead,
お前とお前の連鎖
the chain of you and your past.
何時の世も過去も未来も現在にあるんだ
In any era, the past and the future both exist in the present.
生きていることを愚直に果たせよ
Fulfill your life with honest dedication.
目指せハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy ending!
死んじゃいない
You're not dead,
お前に言っているんだ
I'm talking to you.
幸せを諦めてしまうな 人であるなら
Don't give up on happiness, if you are human!
ただ苦しみに慣れて耐えているだけじゃ
Just getting used to pain and enduring it,
死んでるも同然
is as good as being dead.
屍のアンデッド
A corpse of an undead.
Unhappy? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? O troubled child of humanity.
Unlucky? 人ならざるものも
Unlucky? And even those who are not human,
Be happy! まずは目指せよ 生きているんだろ
Be happy! First, aim for it! You're alive, aren't you?
不幸に浸るも幸せになるのも
Wallowing in unhappiness, or becoming happy,
そう全部全部お前だ
yes, it's all up to you.
古今東西 森羅万象 ピースピース
All times, all places, all creation! Peace, peace!
Past & Future, can't change the past
Past & Future, run for the future
人の在る所に住む例いこと
Troubles that dwell where humans exist,
化け物ばかりの物語
a story full of monsters.
ちょこっと ヤンチャ で
A little mischievous,
ニコっと 元気 な
and smiling energetically,
キラッと スマイル ア ・ イ ・ ド ・ ル ！
a sparkling smile idol!
毎日 もっと 楽しく したい
I want to make every day more fun,
ドンヨク with アドベンチャー
greedy with adventure!
ひらひら スカート も ちゃんと 着こなせる んだ よ
I can carry off a fluttering skirt too!
だから もっともっと 好き に なって も いい よ ？
So, it's okay to fall even more in love with me, you know?
一緒に
Together,
大空 に 飛び た と う
let's fly into the great sky!
光 れ starlight どんな 輝き の 中 も
Shine, starlight! Even amidst any brightness,
強い キラメキ
there is a strong sparkle.
キミ に 届い ているかな ？
I wonder if it's reaching you?
1 ミリ でも 伝われ fight , oh !
Even just a millimeter, let it reach! Fight, oh!
チャージ ！ チャレンジ ！ 全力 アクセル
Charge! Challenge! Full accelerator!
がんばる キミ へ
To you who are doing your best,
一番乗り の スマイル を 贈る
I send my number one smile!
オッケーです！スバルチャンネル！
Okay! Subaru Channel!
Everyday 何があっても みんなで
Everyday, no matter what happens, let's all...
ブルーな気持ちに スバっと駆けつけ
Rushing to your blue feelings in Subaru style,
お助けしちゃうヒーロー
I'm a hero who will rescue you!
弱いハートじゃ いられないから
Because I can't stay with a weak heart,
つよつよでいきましょう！
let's go strong and tough!
ハラハラな水着で
In a thrilling swimsuit,
ドキドキのときめきタイム
it's heart-pounding exciting time!
いつでもおいでよ 一年中パラダイス
Come on over anytime, a paradise all year round!
カウントダウン
Countdown!
曇り空 吹き飛ばそう
Let's blow away the cloudy skies!
上がれサマー！もっとうまく
Rise up, summer! Better yet,
暗闇の中も 眩しく照らす
brightly illuminating even the darkness.
君に見つけてもらえた
Just having you find me,
それだけでも素晴らしい運命なんだ<
that alone is a wonderful destiny.
もっとずっと 道は続いてく
The road keeps going on and on,
夢に向かって
towards our dreams.
いっしょに生きてくれるかな
Will you live together with me?
その手をとって走れ
Take that hand and run!
連れていくよ みんなで
I'll take you along, everyone together!
囁く 恥ずかしいけれど
Whispering is embarrassing, but...
伝えたい想い
the feelings I want to convey,
今なら言える
I can say them now.
君のエールが 力になるよ
Your cheers give me strength.
いつも元気を 分けてくれて
Always sharing your energy with me.
頑張っていけるんだ
I can keep doing my best,
笑って過ごせるんだ 本当に
I can spend my days laughing, truly.
ありがとうのこの気持ちを
With these feelings of gratitude,
歌えサマー！もっと
sing out, summer! More,
輝きの中も 強いきらめき
an even stronger sparkle in the midst of brightness.
君に届いているかな
I wonder if it's reaching you?
1ミリでも伝わればいいな
If even a single millimeter gets through, that would be great.
もっとずっと 道は続いてく
The road keeps going on and on,
夢に向かって
towards our dreams.
いっしょに生きてくれるかな
Will you live together with me?
その手をとって走れ
Take that hand and run!
連れていくよ みんなで
I'll take you along, everyone together!
君とかける スバルチャンネル
Running with you, Subaru Channel!
スバル先輩ありがとうございました！Koboでした！
Thank you so much, Subaru-senpai! This was Kobo!
コボ頑張れー！
Do your best, Kobo!
お誕生日おめでとうー！
Happy Birthday!
誰かのための痛み？
A pain for someone?
僕の願い、やがて散り散り
My wish will soon be scattered.
椅子取りゲームみたい
Like a game of musical chairs,
それでも、息をしていくしかない
but even so, I have no choice but to keep breathing.
まだ、聞こえるか？
Can you still hear it?
とっくのとうに詰まった呼吸
A breath that was choked up long ago.
関係ない、うるせえわ
It doesn't matter, shut up!
自分だけが聞こえている
I'm the only one who can hear it.
安定なんて捨てた
I threw away stability.
もう、すべてを振り切るスピードで
Already, at a speed that shakes off everything.
その瞬間まで、足掻いて ただ、脳絞って
Struggling until that moment, just squeezing my brain
今、見えるとこまで
to as far as I can see now.
この瞬間を飲み干して、また踊って
Drinking down this moment and dancing again,
見たことないもの、見せて
show me something I've never seen before.
「君の代わりはいない」
There's no substitute for you.
もし、誰かが否定しても
Even if someone denies it,
僕の代わりはいない
there's no substitute for me.
違うことない、僕の目覚まし
There's no mistake, it's my awakening.
誰かの祈る手を払った痛み
The pain of brushing away someone's praying hand,
どこから漂う悪意の兆し
a sign of malice drifting from somewhere.
正しさに息を潜めた怒り
The anger that held its breath in righteousness,
それすらも僕に残った光
even that is the light left to me.
誰彼の熱を奪う感覚
The sensation of robbing anyone and everyone's heat,
逃げる気はとうにないぜ、全く
I have absolutely no intention of escaping.
この手が震えるほどの錯覚が、起こした摩擦
The friction caused by the illusion that made my hand tremble.
まだ、見えてるか？
Can you still see it?
とっくにスポットライトを奪った
I've already stolen the spotlight long ago.
関係ない、うるせえわ
It doesn't matter, shut up!
自分だけに聞かせている
I'm only letting myself hear it.
安定なんてやめだ
Stop with the stability.
もう、すべてを振り切るスピードで
Already, at a speed that shakes off everything.
この瞬間だけ、足掻いたって意味ないぜ
Struggling just for this moment is meaningless,
今、見えるとこまで
to as far as I can see now.
第六感で惹きあって、また踊って
Attracting each other with our sixth sense, and dancing again,
見たことないものを見せて
show me something I've never seen before.
今をブチ抜いて！
Break through the present!
もう、ノンストップで脳、擦り切れるまで
Already, non-stop, until our brains wear out.
この瞬間を飲み干して、また踊って
Drinking down this moment and dancing again,
見たことないもの、見せて
show me something I've never seen before.
さあ、この瞬間を飲み干して
Now, drink up this moment,
また踊って
and dance again,
特等席で新しいもの見せて
show me something new from the front row seat.
連れていかれるように
As if being carried away...
踏み出した暗い街へ
I stepped out into the dark streets.
tell me what you need
後追う背中は黒く染まってた
The back I chased was dyed in black.
wait, hold up
悪党？それとも正義？ huh?
A villain? Or justice? Huh?
やりがい searching  馬鹿みたい
Searching for a purpose, like a fool.
目の前の問題は it's too much now
The problems in front of me are too much now.
後回しでもまあ良いじゃん
It's fine to just put them off.
人生の意味結局何？
What is the meaning of life, in the end?
不安定な日々に裏返る声
My voice cracks in these unstable days.
あれこれ言ってる間に
While talking about this and that,
姿を消し去った君は誰？
who are you, who completely disappeared?
曖昧な世界が変わった
The ambiguous world changed,
あの日
on that day.
ど派手に響かせた声が
The voice I let resonate so flashily
まだ今も鳴り止まない
still doesn't stop ringing even now.
紅の夜に心奪われて
With my heart stolen by the crimson night,
このどうしようもない感情に君を映してた
I reflected you in this helpless emotion.
増えてく影を追い
Chasing the multiplying shadows,
気づけば遠い街で
I found myself in a distant town before I knew it.
引き返し
Turning back,
元通りなるのにはもう遅かった
it was already too late to go back to normal.
wait, hold up
sos 逃げ道がないの
SOS, there's no way out.
え、ちょまって
What? Hold on a second.
how is it my fault?
レフト、ライト ステップからの
Left, right, from the step,
get down に見せかけて clap
pretending to get down, clap.
からかっておいて立場は対等？
Are we equals even though you mock me?
助けてやって何その態度
What's with that attitude after I helped you?
不満の中で生まれる依存症
Addiction born out of frustration,
垣間見えるのは愛
what I catch a glimpse of is love.
退屈な世界が変わった
The boring world changed,
あの日
on that day.
ど派手に響かせた声が
The voice I let resonate so flashily
まだ今も鳴り止まない
still doesn't stop ringing even now.
紅の夜に心奪われて
With my heart stolen by the crimson night,
このどうしようもない感情に君を映してた
I reflected you in this helpless emotion.
このどうしようもない感情に
In this helpless emotion,
君を映してた
I reflected you.
はい、はい腹から声出して
Yes, yes, make a sound from your stomach.
そんなんじゃ痛い目に遭いまっせ
You're gonna have a bad time like that.
勝敗かけた歌合戦
A singing battle with victory and defeat at stake,
枯れそうな地声で
with a natural voice about to wither,
まだ歌うのさ
I'm still singing.
ど派手に響かせた声が
The voice I let resonate so flashily
まだ今も鳴り止まない
still doesn't stop ringing even now.
紅の夜に心奪われて
With my heart stolen by the crimson night,
このどうしようもない感情に君を映してた
I reflected you in this helpless emotion.
はい、はい腹から声出して
Yes, yes, make a sound from your stomach.
そんなんじゃ痛い目に遭いまっせ
You're gonna have a bad time like that.
紅の夜に心奪われて
With my heart stolen by the crimson night,
このどうしようもない感情に君を映してた
I reflected you in this helpless emotion.
One, one, one for me, don, don
One, one, one for me
関係探って
Grasping for a connection,
あ、ごめんねって
oh, sorry about that,
意味がないね
it's meaningless.
手繰るだけ アルゴリズム 満ち足りない
Just tracing the algorithm, it's not enough.
じゃあ どうなりたい？
Then, what do you want to be?
そっと暴いて 二重で被る幻想
Slightly exposing the double-layered illusion,
優しい 言葉並べて
lining up kind words,
二人 お揃いに甘えて
the two of us, indulging in being matching...
演じて見せてるのは
The performance you're putting on...
誰の為に
Who is it for?
ただ泣きたいように 笑っていたんだ
I was laughing, as if I just wanted to cry.
One, one, one for me
偽りの perfect fake
A perfect fake of lies.
愛なんては分かっちゃいないんだ
I don't understand things like love.
One, one, one for me
いつの間にか perfect fake
Before I knew it, a perfect fake.
One, one, one for me, don, don, be fake
One, one, one for me, be, be, be fake
重ね重ねお詫びします 気持ちのない口癖
I apologize repeatedly, a habit of speaking without any feeling.
優しさにずるさも履き違えて重ね重ね
Confusing kindness with slyness, repeatedly...
あぁその吐息だけで 満たされるマスク
Ah, a mask filled only with that breath,
まだ二重で縛って 心の
still binding it in double layers, my heart...
皆でさぁ ずっと取り繕っている
Everyone is pretending all the time
本当の顔は誰のためで
Who is that real face for?
だんだん苦しくなるね
It's getting more and more painful, isn't it?
お揃いの甘えの前の前ならえ
Following the pattern of matching sweetness
ただ泣いて ないで 笑っていたいよ
I just want to smile instead of crying
O wise of me いつまでも Free free free
O wise of me, always Free free free
愛なんて分かっちゃいないんだ
I don't understand love at all
O wise of me いつの日にか Deep fake
O wise of me, someday Deep fake...
脱いでみたい
...I want to try taking it off
演技でもないなら
If it's not even acting...
それまでただ よせのから
...until then, just drafting the sky
胸に秘めている Deep fake
Keeping a Deep fake hidden in my heart
ただ泣いて ないで 笑っていたんだ
I was laughing instead of crying
O wise of me 偽りの Deep fake
O wise of me, a fake Deep fake
愛なんて分かっちゃいないんだ
I don't understand love at all
O wise of me いつの間にか Deep fake
O wise of me, before I knew it, Deep fake
O wise of me... Deep fake
はあ…はあ…はあ…みんな、どうでしたか？
*pant* *pant* *pant* Everyone, how was it?
いや、今回はですね、あのハウスダンスに初めて挑戦したんですけれども
So, this time, I challenged myself with house dancing for the first time.
あの、2ヶ月で、あの、詰め込んで踊れてましたか？
I crammed it all in just two months. Did it look like I was dancing?
いや、「めっちゃ頑張った」ってコメントが書いてくれてるんだろうなぁ、いやはや
I'm sure everyone is writing comments like "you worked really hard!" Oh my.
でね、あの「波に名前をつけること、僕らの呼吸に終わりがあること」って曲では
And in the song "Naming the Waves, Knowing Our Breath Will End"...
リフトをしたり、あのクルクル回って、あれも初めてやりました。踊れてたら嬉しいね！
...we did lifts, and spun around, which was also a first for me. I'd be happy if I danced it well!
いや、ゲストのね、ハコ太郎先輩とも、いけいけに踊って
I danced energetically with our guest, Hako-taro senpai...
スバル先輩、憧れのスバル先輩と2人きりでドキドキタイムしちゃったり
...and had a heart-fluttering moment alone with my admired Subaru-senpai...
ロボ子先輩と、いろは先輩と、らでんちゃんとはもう対決して
I also battled Roboco-senpai, Iroha-senpai, and Raden-chan...
ロボ子さんとマリンちゃんはカップルで
...Roboco-san and Marine-chan acted as a couple...
AZKiちゃんとはかっこよく、いや〜
...and had a cool duet with AZKi-chan. Oh my...
ゲストパートもたくさんね、素晴らしいのがあったんじゃないでしょうか？
...there were so many amazing things in the guest parts, wasn't there?
ということで、皆さん、何か忘れてませんか？
And with that, everyone, aren't you forgetting something?
ね、皆さん、ちょっと水宮の休憩タイムもね、もうそろそろ終わらないといけない
You know, Umi's break time also has to end pretty soon.
よし、立つか！よいしょ！
Alright, time to stand up! Up we go!
はい、ということで、なんとですね、こんな感じで言うのもなんなんですが
Yes! And so, believe it or not, I don't know how to say this, but...
新曲が出ます！イェーイ！
...a new song is coming out! Yay!
初のオリジナル楽曲！フフフフフ！
My very first original song! *giggle*
やばい、体が疲れた、よっこらしょ、はい
Oh no, my body is so tired. Up we go. Okay.
ということで、えっと作詞・作曲・編曲は、サトダユーリさんに作ってもらいました！
And so, the lyrics, composition, and arrangement were done by Satoda Yuri-san!
ありがとう！ドンドンパフパフ！ドンドンパフパフ！
Thank you! *trumpet fanfare*!
はい、このあと、すぐMV公開がね、この配信が終わったあとあるのですが、リダイレクトで飛びます
Yes, the MV will be released right after this stream ends, and you'll be redirected there.
そしてデジタルリリースは、今日の0時からなので、たくさん聴いてくれると嬉しいです！
Also, the digital release starts at midnight tonight, so I'd be happy if you listened to it a lot!
じゃあ、ちょっと早速なんですが、その新曲をお披露目しちゃおうかな？
So, without further ado, shall I perform that new song for you?
いや、どんな楽曲なんだろう？気になるな！どんな楽曲なんだろう？いきます！
Wow, what kind of song is it? I'm so curious! What kind of song is it? Here we go!
うみゃうみゃ うみゃうみゃ うみゃうみゃ うみゃうみゃ
Umi-unya, Umi-unya...
くるるん くるるん
Kururun, kururun
あ〜そろそろご飯の時間かな？
Ah, is it almost mealtime?
あ、でもでも やっぱやっぱ 家から一歩も出たくないっ！
Ah, but but, no no, I don't want to take a single step out of the house!
こんな時はそうだ！お水とのどが
In times like this, that's right! Water and throat...
説明しよう！極限までお腹を空かし美味しくいただくのだ！
Let me explain! Starving myself to the limit and eating it deliciously!
めんどうい めんどうい マジめんどういわ けっきょくぐだぐだ時間とけたわ
It's a hassle, a hassle, seriously a hassle. In the end, everything is time melting away
ぴりんぴりん 5回目アラーム コンビニいこー
Pi-rin pi-rin, the 5th alarm. Let's go to the convenience store
わちゃわちゃ はちゃめちゃ 奇想天外 ドタバタ てんやわんや見逃せない
Chaotic, messy, whimsical, bustling, hectic, don't miss it!
ピンチだって ちょちょいのちょいで てやっ てやっ そりゃ そりゃ 万事解決☆
Even in a pinch, it's a piece of cake! Te-ya, te-ya, so-ryah, so-ryah, everything is solved☆
うみゃうみゃ うみゃうみゃ 美味しくなぁれ あれもこれも全部食べたいな
Umi-unya, Umi-unya, be delicious! I want to eat everything
ぱくぱく うみゃうみゃ ハピネスライフ 食べて寝て遊んで また食べる
Pak-pak, Umi-unya, Happiness Life! Eat, sleep, play, and eat again
ぺこぺこ ぺこぺこ はらぺこちゃん うみゃうみゃ うまくいきません
Hungry, hungry, hungry girl! Umi-unya, it's not going well
ひとまずご飯をお腹いっぱい 食べさせてよ
For now, let me eat my fill of food
うみゃうみゃ うみゃうみゃ うにゃうにゃ うみゃうみゃ
Umi-unya, Umi-unya...
あーいい天気！
Ah, such nice weather!
あの雲、ソフトクリームみたい！
That cloud looks like soft-serve ice cream!
あ、あっちはわたがし！
Ah, that one's cotton candy!
雲ってふわふわで美味しそう...
Clouds look so fluffy and delicious...
人生で一回は食べてみたいよね～
I want to try eating one at least once in my life~
じゃない！
Wait, no!
しんどい しんどい マジしんどいわ
Tired, tired, I'm seriously tired,
現実逃避 何度もしちゃうわ
I end up escaping reality over and over again.
妄想 空想 頭が暴走
Delusions, daydreams, my head is running wild.
カツオ食べたーい！
I want to eat bonito!
だらだら ぐうたら 怠惰全開
Slobbing around, idling, laziness fully open,
ネガティブ思考もご愛嬌です保存
even my negative thinking is part of my charm!
世界だってぽいぽいのぽいで
Even the world is tossed aside like "poi-poi-poi"...
えいやっ！えいやっ！どりゃっ！どりゃっ！ねじ伏せちゃうぞ☆
Bam! Bam! Pow! Pow! I'll twist it into submission!☆
うみゃ うみゃ うみゃ うみゃ お腹空いたら
Umyu-umyu-umyu-umyu, when I'm hungry,
突撃！隣の晩御飯（ちょーらい！）
raid! The next-door neighbor's dinner! (Give me some!)
ぱくぱくうみゃうみゃしあわせタイム
Munch-munch, umyu-umyu, happy time!
食欲で生きてます
I live for my appetite!
だからどうかお願い
So please, I beg of you...
このおなかを満たして 神様
satisfy this stomach, O God!
食べたーい！寝たーい！
I want to eat! I want to sleep!
難しいことは何も考えたくない
I don't want to think about anything complicated!
あとあと、みんなでお菓子パーティもしたーい！
And also, I want to have a sweets party with everyone!
うみゃうみゃうみゃうみゃおいしくなーれ
Umyu-umyu-umyu-umyu, become delicious!
あれもこれも全部食べたいな
I want to eat this, that, and everything!
ぱくぱくうみゃうみゃハピネスライフ
Munch-munch, umyu-umyu, happiness life!
食べて寝て遊んでまた食べ
Eat, sleep, play, and eat again!
ペコペコペコペコ腹ペコだ
Hungry, hungry, hungry, hungry, my stomach is empty!
うみゃうみゃうみゃ美味しく召しませ
Umyu-umyu-umyu, enjoy the deliciousness!
ひとまずごはんをお腹いっぱい
For now, let me eat my fill of food...
食べさせて
Please feed me!
まだ足りない
It's still not enough!
もっともっと食べさせて
Let me eat more and more!
新曲どうだったー？可愛かったでしょう？
How was the new song? Cute, right?
おうちに、お呼ばれしちゃったみんながね、
Everyone who got invited to my house,
ちょっと距離近めでね、
keeping the distance a bit close,
ASMRボイスが...
the ASMR voice...
こんな感じで、まぁちょっと適当なんですけど、そんな感じのボイスになっております！
...is like this. It's a bit of an example, but that's how it is!
こちら！
This one!
数量限定じゃ...
It's not...
ない！
limited quantity!
ので、焦らずに、みんなゆっくりで大丈夫です！
So don't rush, you can all take your time!
グッズは、22時、じゅ、ん？
The merchandise will be on sale from 22:00, ten... hm?
22時10分から販売開始です！
Sales will start from 22:10!
直筆のサインとかもね、全部、もう何もかも数量限定じゃないので！
The hand-written signatures and everything else are not limited in quantity!
あの、すうちゃんのサインも、あの、付いてきますのでね、フルセットを買ったら！
Suu-chan's signature will also be included if you buy the full set!
みなさん、よろしくお願いします！ぜひ！
Everyone, thank you in advance! Please do!
買ってね！
Buy it, okay!
いっぱい買ってねー！
Buy lots of them!
はい！
Yes!
ということで、以上、みにみあによるグッズ紹介でしたー！
So, that was the merchandise introduction by Mini Mia!
うわー！
Whoa!
はーい！ということで、みにみあありがとうー！
Alright! Thank you, Mini Mia!
なんか結構ミスってたな。まぁ、みにみあだからね。まぁ、すうじゃないから。
She made quite a few mistakes. Well, she is Mini Mia. She is not Suu.
まぁ、仕方ないか！仕方ないか！
Well, I guess it can't be helped! It can't be helped!
ということで、誕生日の3Dライブはどうだったでしょうか！
So, how was my birthday 3D live?
憧れのホロライブに入ってから、みんなにいーっぱい応援してもらって、ここまで来れました！
Ever since joining Hololive, I've received so much support to get this far!
みんなに少しでもね、「かっこよかった」とか、「すうのこと応援しててよかった」って思ってもらえてると、とっても嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you felt I was cool, or that you're glad to support me!
MVはこのあとすぐ公開で、リダイレクトで飛ぶので、チャンネルはそのままでよろしくお願いします！
The MV will premiere right after this, and you will be redirected, so stay tuned!
ということで、みんな、これからもよろしくね！ありがとうー！
So, please continue to support me, everyone! Thank you!
じゃあ、ばいばーい！
Bye-bye!
まったねー！
See ya!
ずうりすへ
To Suuris,
ずうをみててくれて おうえんしてくれてありがとう!!
Thank you for watching Suu and supporting me!!
そのまいにちのなかにえらんでもらえるような
So that I can be chosen as part of your daily life,
じぶんのかつどうをこれからもコツコツがんばっていくので
I will continue to work hard on my activities step-by-step,
みまもっててね
so please watch over me.
ずうががんばれるのはずうりすのおかげ!!
Suu can do her best because of Suuris!!